Amlan Banaji

Curriculum Vitae

Website: amlan-banaji.github.io

Email: afb8 "at" st-andrews.ac.uk

Nationality: UK

Website. annan-banaji.gitiiub.ic

PhD student in Mathematics at St Andrews

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am primarily interested in the geometry and dimension theory of fractal sets and measures. I have worked extensively with fractals generated by conformal and non-conformal iterated function systems. Much of my research has focused on interpolating between different notions of dimension. I am interested in finding connections between fractal geometry and other areas of mathematics.

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

- 1. Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors (with J. M. Fraser) To appear in **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society**. arXiv
- 2. Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions (with A. Rutar) Annales Fennici Mathematici 47 (2022) 939–960. arXiv
- 3. Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence (with I. Kolossváry)
 Submitted. arXiv
- 4. Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets (with J. M. Fraser) Submitted. <u>arXiv</u>
- 5. Generalised intermediate dimensions *Submitted. arXiv*

EDUCATION

University of St Andrews

2019–present

PhD Mathematics (in progress)

Topic: Fractal geometry and dimension theory

With the **Analysis Research Group**

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the Leverhulme Trust

University of St Andrews

2018-2019

MSc Mathematics, Distinction

GPA: 19.5/20. Ranked 1st in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015–2018

BA (Hons) Mathematics

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

Thomas Tallis Sixth Form

2013-2015

A-Levels:

 $Mathematics(A^*)$, $Further\ Mathematics(A^*)$, $Physics(A^*)$, $Chemistry(A^*)$, History(A), $Extended\ Project\ Qualification(A^*,\ equivalent\ to\ half\ an\ A\ level)$

PRIZE

2019: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best taught postgraduate student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

TALKS

I have given 17 talks (listed at <u>amlan-banaji.github.io/talks</u>) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, June 2022)
- <u>Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting</u> (ICMS, Edinburgh (March 2022) and online (March 2021))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, May 2022)
- Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER) (Warwick, May 2022 and March 2021)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, May 2022, October 2021 and June 2020)

EXPERIENCE

• Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

2019 – 2021: MT2502 Analysis (8 groups total) *2021*: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- *2018 onwards*: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.
- 2017: internship at market research company Kantar TNS, working as a **data scientist** for the social media team, using Python.

SERVICE

- 2022: Referee for Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A and J. Math. Anal. Appl.
- 2021: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- 2019–2021: **Treasurer** of St Andrews Mindfulness Society.

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES

- 2022–present: <u>London Mathematical Society</u>
- 2020–present: Edinburgh Mathematical Society
- 2019–present: Associate Member of the <u>Institute of Mathematics and its Applications</u> (AMIMA)

INTERESTS AND SKILLS

- Languages: English (native), German (conversational, A* at GCSE), Hindi (conversational)
- Music: Piano (grade 8), Clarinet (toured Canada and Venice)
- **Sport:** running, badminton, chess